<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>francisbegyn</title>
    <link>https://about.francisbegyn.be/</link>
    <description>Recent content on francisbegyn</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 16 Aug 2018 12:58:17 +0200</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://about.francisbegyn.be/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Making debian packages on Arch Linux</title>
      <link>https://about.francisbegyn.be/posts/deb-packages-arch/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 16 Aug 2018 12:58:17 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://about.francisbegyn.be/posts/deb-packages-arch/</guid>
      <description>Lately I&amp;rsquo;ve been helping with a little APT repo, and it&amp;rsquo;s been fun. The thing I struggled a bit with was making a .deb package on my system (&amp;ldquo;Hey, did you know I use Arch Linux?&amp;rdquo;). Not because this is badly documented, but a lot of the documentation is actually making use of devscripts, dh_make or other helpers, which for some unkown reason all refuse to work on my system.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Docker, trustworthy or shady?</title>
      <link>https://about.francisbegyn.be/posts/maliciousdocker/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 17 Jun 2018 01:38:45 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://about.francisbegyn.be/posts/maliciousdocker/</guid>
      <description>When I saw the article about docker images on dockerhub being infected with cryptocurrency mining malware, I couldn&amp;rsquo;t help but write something about my feelings about docker.
Docker? According to wikipedia
 Docker is a computer program that performs operating-system-level virtualization also known as containerization.[6] It is developed by Docker, Inc.[7] Docker is primarily developed for Linux, where it uses the resource isolation features of the Linux kernel such as cgroups and kernel namespaces, and a union-capable file system such as OverlayFS and others[8] to allow independent &amp;ldquo;containers&amp;rdquo; to run within a single Linux instance, avoiding the overhead of starting and maintaining virtual machines (VMs).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Setting up a reverse proxy, traefik</title>
      <link>https://about.francisbegyn.be/posts/traefik/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 17 Jun 2018 00:30:40 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://about.francisbegyn.be/posts/traefik/</guid>
      <description>So I run a few services at home, primarily for testing and development only. I simply do not have the infrastructure or network to do so for anything I deem important. That said, being able to test some things quickly on a system where I have to care little about introducing breaking changes is very handy (not that I often do, just when it happens I don&amp;rsquo;t do it on production :p ).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>About me</title>
      <link>https://about.francisbegyn.be/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://about.francisbegyn.be/about/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;m a 22-year-old belgian electrical engineering student at the Ghent University. I&amp;rsquo;m also active in multiple event organistations mainly as a logistical/technical person. To relax, I play some guitar or tinker with linux machines.
The blog I have here is something to air my rants and to keep &amp;ldquo;guides&amp;rdquo; (for the lack of a better word) for some of the things that I do. They are by no means meant to be toturials.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>